Ryan Chapel – Seasoned Web Developer

425-830-8694 ryan.chapel@gmail.com Snoqualmie, WA

I'm a full-stack web developer with 18+ years of experience **shipping quality projects** and **making the web fun**. I consider **fairness** and **compassion** as two of my most valuable tools, and just want to help make **useful** websites that keep people engaged.

My motto for the web is "Reduce Friction, Increase Joy".

Skills & Tech

- JavaScript / TypeScript
- React / React Native / Next.js
- Headless development
- Node.js / Express.js
- Tailwind / Sass / CSS
- Al Tools (Co-Pilot, Cursor, etc)
- Adobe AEM & EDS
- AWS Amplify
- Storybook
- A11y / Performance
- Figma / Photoshop
- Web3 / Solidity

- Team & employee growth
- Mentorship / leadership
- Collaboration / inclusivity
- Innovation / Ideas
- Effective communication
- Team training / skill teaching

Experience

FREELANCE FULL-STACK DEVELOPER & CONSULTANT — 12/2024-PRESENT

Creating & implementing simple solutions to help small businesses thrive. Mostly utilizing React, TypeScript, Node.js, Express.js, and more.

SENIOR MANAGER, EXPERIENCE TECHNOLOGY @ HERO DIGITAL; REMOTE — 09/2023-12/2024

Led a large front-end team to launch the new LPGA.com site using React, React Native, & Next.js. This led to a **65% increase in site performance**. I managed a thriving team of front-end developers working on different projects while also writing code in multiple codebases / CMS myself. Created multiple PoC pages for business development using different front-end tech, including Adobe EDS.

SENIOR MANAGER, FRONT-END DISCIPLINE @ AVIONOS (MERGED W/ HERO DIGITAL); REMOTE — 08/2020-09/2023

Hired to grow the FED team within the org as well as led FE work in various projects, mostly pertaining to React and Adobe AEM. I **expanded my team by more than 400%** and at the same time I led multiple client projects, **created training for devs**, nurtured direct reports' growth through goals and planning, etc.

FOUNDER, DESIGNER, MAKER, & DEVELOPER @ PAPERNFTS (PERSONAL); SNOQUALMIE, WA — 09/2021-09/2022 LEAD UI DEVELOPER & DEV MANAGER @ REDAWNING; SEATTLE, WA — 02/2017-03/2020

Created the RedAwning **React Native app from scratch**, led the redesign of RedAwning.com in 2017.

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, AEM @ R2INTEGRATED; SEATTLE, WA — 04/2016-02/2017

MANAGER & SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER @ APOLLO EDUCATION GROUP; SEATTLE, WA — 02/2006-04/2016

Education

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, COMPUTER SYSTEMS @ CITY UNIVERSITY OF SEATTLE — 2006

On The Web

chapeljuice.dev linkedin.com/in/ryanchapel ryanchapel.com github.com/chapeljuice